# **David Taylor**



Austin, TX 78723



**512.514.3706** 



david@codewizard.app





Ambitious and flexible problem solver with 5 years experience in solving problems and building solutions. Seeking a developer role to apply my attention to detail and to collaborate with the goal of creating innovative and reliable solutions to technical problems. Currently at University of Texas Coding Bootcamp to improve, solidify, and polish my skills as a developer.

## Skills

Server side programming: NodeJS, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, GraphQL, ApolloQL

Client side programming: Dynamic, responsive UI execution with JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS

Frameworks and packages: React.js, Angular.js, Laravel, Express, TypeScript

Project management tools: Git, NPM, Composer, Babel, Webpack, RollUp, Storybook

General programming: data structures, algorithms, CI/CD pipelines, experimenting with new packages Essential skills: Communication, collaboration, problem solving, active listening, leadership, flexibility

# Experience

# **Body Wizard Medicine**

Austin, TX

#### **WEBMASTER**

AUGUST 2017 - DECEMBER 2021

- Built and maintained a landing page for general business purposes
- Work independently to design and develop web software for a medical portal, used for appointment scheduling, email and text reminders, billing, electronic health record management, inventory, and prescription management
- Integrated above software with over 5 external APIs for Twilio, SendGrid, and Stripe, as well as various medical APIs

#### OWNER / ACUPUNCTURIST

JULY 2013 - DECEMBER 2021

- Opened LLC for the practice of Traditional Chinese Medicine
- Maintained marketing presence through use of Facebook, Instagram, and Google Ads
- Identified and diagnosed complex disease patterns for over a 1000 patients with a wide range of medical issues
- Known for wonderful bedside manner with delicate situations and excellent clinical results

## Education

## Full Stack Coding Bootcamp / University of Texas Austin

JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

Comprehensive courses including collaborative teamwork and best practices in addition to standard coding skills Projected Completion: September 6 2022

- Worked on dozens of projects server side, client side, and command line
- Completed three team projects, a cost-of-living comparison tool, an existentialist RPG, and a social network for book enthusiasts
- Successfully led teams to the completion of our projects

**Udemy** / Online AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT

Full Stack Developer Courses with the following certificates of completion

Web Developer Bootcamp - September '21, Typescript Complete Developers Guide - September '21,

Modern React with Redux - September '21, Modern Angular Bootcamp - October '21,

MERN Stack Front to Back - October '21.